# **SERGIO CHAVEZ LAZO**

#### SUMMARY

Data scientist and sociologist. Experienced in designing and implementing data-driven organisational strategies, teaching and academic research. With a very successful interdisciplinary background that allows to contemplate and tackle challenges from different perspectives. Perennial learner and proud self-learner.

Portfolio of personal projects:

https://sergiochavezlazo.github.io/ProjectsxPortafolio/

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sergio-chavez-lazo-212378170/

#### **EDUCATION**

MSc Data Science and Social Analytics – In progress (Distinction Overall) – Winner of 'Beca Bicentenario' - Government of Peru **University of Manchester** 

BA, Sociology - Academic Excellence (1st place), 06/2020 **Pontificia Universidad Catolica del Peru (PUCP)** 

Specialisation in Behavioural Economics (120 hours), 12/20 **Universidad del Pacífico** 

Specialisation in Applied Statistics (180 hours), 02/2021 National School of Statistics and Informatics (ENEI)

Professional specialisation in Data Science, 05/2020 **IBM** 

Specialisation in Design Thinking (50 hours), 10/2020 **Instituto Europeo de Posgrado (IEP)** 

#### CONTACT

**Address:** Wilmslow Park- 211 Hathersage Road – Manchester M13 0.IP

**Phone**: UK: 07759013211/

Peru: 958582763

Email:

sergio.chavezl@pucp.edu.pe

#### SKILLS

- Research strategies
- Data processing
- Quantitative and qualitative analysis
- Information visualization and presentation

#### LANGUAGES

- Spanish
- English Advanced (TOEFL Score: 108)
- Portuguese Intermediate

#### **SOFTWARE**

- SPSS
- Python
- SQL
- R Studio
- Power BI
- Excel Data Model
- Data Studio

#### **ACADEMIC MERITS**

Academic excellence: first place in the graduating class of the sociology major and the faculty of social sciences in the 2019-2 academic semester.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

Analyst in the Office of Strategic and Administrative Monitoring - Vice-Rectorate of Research (VRI) PUCP, 10/2020 – 08/2022.

Elaboration of benchmarking, visualisation, and systematisation of PUCP research data. Founder member of the Data Management Committee.

# Area leader of diffusion area in Decision Lab, 08/2020 - 12/2021 Prospective Research Group for Public Policy-PUCP.

Organiser of dissemination of research presented at the Nobec Talks by the University of Pennsylvania.

Teaching assistant for the courses "Statistics for sociological analysis 1 and 2" and "Methodology of quantitative research 1 and 2" at the Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú 08/2021-07/2022

Teaching assistant with high ratings according to the semester student surveys.

Statistical assistant in the elaboration of the book "Estudio Jóvenes 2019-Fundación SM" supporting the group "Edades de la Vida y Educación (EVE)" - 04/2021-09/2021.

Management of databases for the generation of tables, graphs and statistical analysis requested by the authors.

#### Research assistant at PUCP, 08/2020 - 12/2020 CISEPA-PUCP

Assistant of Dr. Robin Cavagnoud. The documentation, systematization, and visualization of information on the socio-demographic transition in Peru from 1961 to the present was successfully completed.

## Intern in the area of Project Coordination, 03/2018 - 12/2019 Institute of Public Opinion - PUCP

Active member of the development of proposals, information gathering, data processing and analysis of qualitative and quantitative results of various social, business and public opinion consultancies.

#### Research Assistant, 07/2020 - 08/2020 - CUANTI

Active member of the team in charge of developing methodologies for teaching quantitative and qualitative research consultancies.

Winner of the 2019 PUCP programme to support the development of undergraduate theses (PADET).

Winner of the research monograph competition of the faculty of social sciences 2018.

Finalist of the "first step" contest of the University of Lima for innovative projects.

Co-author of workbook: "the influence of associativity on productive opportunities: the case of 4 agricultural associations in Moquegua" (Bobadilla, et al. 2019).

Author of the article "Religiosidad y aprobación católica de la intervención política de la iglesia y sus líderes en el Perú" (Religiosidad y aprobación Católica de la intervención política de la Iglesia y sus líderes en el Perú). (Chávez, 2019) published in the journal La Colmena.

Bachelor's thesis approved unanimously and with distinction

#### **HOBBIES**

Outstanding powerlifting athlete: National junior champion Peru 2019

Reading books and watching anime and stand up comedy shows

Collector of graphic novels

Former top Pokémon and Yu Gi Oh competitive player